# Claudia Chu

Address: Flat B, 13/F, Tower 3. Cornin Garden, 2 Po On Road, Sham Shui Po, HK Cell Phone: 9619 5648 Email Address: cclaudia 619@hotmail.com

#### **PROFILE**

With 5 years' experience in the accounting field, I had a long and successful career in accounting and more specifically in the area of auditing. I am extremely knowledgeable about audit, compliance and advisory, books and records maintenance, treasury and banking support. As an auditor for 4 years, I respond well to deadlines and targets and I like to see tangible results. I am very fortunate to work on challenging, unique tasks distinctive from regular works.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **HLB Hodgson Impey Cheng Limited,** Assistant Manager

Feb2013-present

- Extensive experience in audits of listed companies (hotel and manufacturing industry), medium to large sized private companies. In particular, specialises in statutory audits of investment funds and licensed corporations registered under the Securities and Futures Commission (SFC).
- Assist in the completion of audit assignments and to ensure that all work is performed in an efficient and effective manner
- Undertake work on audit areas in accordance with the firm's requirements, and with the specific
  instructions provided in the planning documentation and during the audit briefing while being the job in
  charge
- Identify any problems arising during the course of the assignment and to report these to the audit manager immediately, together with appropriate recommendations
- Deal with clients at all times in a professional manner, and to ensure that the client receives a high quality and responsive service
- Mainly work with the fund house, asset management and securities industries (i.e. BOCI-Prudential, HSBC Unit Trust Hong Kong, Amicorp, Maples, Apex, DBS (unit trust), Success Securities, RHB OSK, Orient finance (Hong Kong))

#### Union Alpha C.P.A. Ltd (HK), China Team Trainee

Oct 2011 - Feb 2013

- Establishment of WFOE (Wholly Foreign Owned Enterprise), liaison office, branch office and other forms of enterprises
- Provide accounting service such as compliance and advisory, books and records maintenance, financial control and banking
- Declare both corporate and individual taxes for clients with compliance and advisory, planning and administration, international assignment support
- Provide human resources services for the clients by conducting payroll, social securities administration and employment matters
- Dispose company secretarial services with compliance and advisory, administration and government filings
- Conducted corporate reorganisation and re-structuring, i.e. liquidation and de-registration

### PricewaterhouseCoopers (HK), Trainee Assistant

Aug 2010 - Sep 2010 & Jun 2009-Jul 2009

- Participated in various projects and have learned how to communicate effectively with fellow team members and client staff at all levels
- Organised paperwork, provided front-line internal client support, effective minute keeping, stock ordering and diary management by setting up targets to archive daily workload
- Knowledge of basic bookkeeping and accounting procedures
- Responsible for several testing i.e. Alternative-test, cut-off test, search for unrecorded liability, test for materiality

#### PCCW (HK), Summer Intern in Finance Team

Jun2010-Aug2010

- Working under the Global Finance team, responsible for defining invoices for the creditors and the staff's expenses and data entry
- Built professional working relationships with staff in other companies e.g. worked with external auditors on preparation of financial statements

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Durham (UK)

Oct 2008 - Jun 2011

<u>Major:</u> Bachelor of Arts, Accounting and Finance, Obtained Second Class ( Division One) Honours

<u>Activities and Societies:</u> Member and volunteer of DUCK (Durham University charities kommittee), Durham Finance Society; Swimming team and Chinese Students & Scholars Association

**Abbots Bromley School for Girls (UK)** 

Sep 2006 - Jun2008

A-Level: Maths(B), Art(B), Business(C), Chinese(B)

AS-Level: Further Maths (C)

Prize: UK senior mathematical challenges (Bronze Mental)

Activities and Societies: Volunteers of Staffordshire Country Council Millennium

Volunteers; School house perfect and Overseas co-ordinator

Our Lady's College (HK)

Sep 2001- Jun 2006

HKCEE: Chinese (D), English (D), Maths (E), Religious Studies (D), Art (E), Accounting (E),

Chinese History (E)

Activities: Captain of swimming team; House's co-ordinator

# **PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS**

- Semi-finalist of Hong Kong Institute of Certified Public Accountants Qualification Programme (HKICPA QP)
  (Passed module: A, B, C & D)
- LCCI (London Chamber of Commerce and Industry)-Level 1 & 2 Certificate in Book-Keeping (Result: Credit)

# **IT SKILLS**

- Fully competent with all aspects of Microsoft Office (Word, PowerPoint, Excel & Access) and Quick Book Pro
- Basic knowledge of Bloomberg
- Proficient internet researcher-Knowledge databases
- Typing skills of Chinese word processing (速成)

#### **LANGUAGES**

• Native in Cantonese, fluent in Mandarin & English

## **AVAILABILITY**

• Two month's notice